## Lorenzo Girardi SRE Team Manager



#### PERSONAL DETAILS

Lorenzo Girardi Via cacciatori delle alpi 19 Castronno (Varese) italy

M: 00393402892734

<u>E:</u>

lorenzo.girardi@gmail.com

**PGP** 

E: lorenzo@ethzero.it

E: I@k8s.it

DOB: 16/02/1983 Driving license: YES Nationality: Italian

#### AREAS OF EXPERIENCE

<u>Site reliability engineer</u>

Datacenter migration

People management

Capacity plan

Virtualization technology

**Networking** 

Cloud

Operating systems

HA infrastructure

HS infrastructure

**Monitoring** 

Kubernetes

PCI DSS

**Automation** 

**Architecture** 

#### PERSONAL SUMMARY

Highly competent and organized technology site reliability engineer with experience in high scalability environment and in high availability.

Autonomous management of large projects and implementation with the latest smart tools.

Extensive knowledge of monitoring, applications behavior and data security within guidelines to ensure compliance and report on possible improvements.

Managing teams working in order to reach the business goal.

Interested in a new challenges , opportunity and job reality in a large and complex company
Continuously improving my knowledge on new

technologies.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

**SRE Team Manager - BravoNEXT sa** jan 2019 - present

SRE Team Leader - BravoNEXT sa mid 2016 - 2018

**System administrator - BravoNEXT sa** jan 2012 - mid 2016

Acting as manager and technical lead to identify and implement new projects in a large heterogeneous environment

### **Duties:**

- Maintenance existing environment
- Improve high availability of applications through open source software solutions and physical appliance
- Monitoring server and applications java / .net in order to evaluate capability plans and virtual machines requirements
- Extensive knowledge on network infrastructure
- Planning new projects from scratch, choosing best environment available
- Puppet modules configurations

#### PERSONAL SKILLS

Technically minded

Pro-active

<u>Analitycal</u>

#### **PROFESSIONAL SKILLS**

<u>java – tomcat – jboss –</u> <u>springboot – docker –</u> <u>javamelody – jmx</u>

<u>.net - iis - sql server -</u> <u>cluster WSFC - alwaysON -</u> iis ARR - cluster NLB

<u>apache - mod balancer -</u> <u>mod proxy balancer - mod</u> jk - mod cluster

<u>nginx - vts module - ingress - traefik</u>

<u>vmware esxi - veeam</u> <u>backup / replication</u>

rhev - ovirt

AWS - s3 - vpc - peering - loadbalancer - cloudformation -opsworks

Azure – powershell cli – database as service

<u>puppet - jenkins - pipeline - rundeck - spacewalk-</u> ansible - terraform

<u>Monitoring - nagios</u> <u>handlers - cacti - grafana -</u> collectd - influxdb - carbon

<u>ldap - active directory -</u> <u>bind - domain trust -</u> <u>domain hierarchy</u>

<u>openvpn - strongswan -</u> <u>openswan - site to site -</u> road warriors

<u>k8s - kubernetes - docker -</u> <u>flanneld - etcd</u>

google cloud platform

- Tomcat/springboot configurations
- Active directory, openIdap, ms dns, bind
- Linux machines configurations, sssd ,disk acl,lvm,init
- Linux skilled administrator
- Windows machines iis /sql
- Vm infrastructure management 800+ linux server centos 6 - 7 and Ubuntu
- Kubernetes infrastructure management 100+ nodes 2000+ pods
- Cluster management RHEV , vmware esxi
- Infrastructure management 100+ windows servers 2008-2012
- Solution architect MS sql environment in HA and LB for IIS applications
- Solution architect AWS environment s3 vpc peering
- Solution architect Azure environment
- Network management ipsec open source strongswan , openswan and cisco and fortinet
- Develop and maintaining kubernetes cluster
- Coordinate people in projects ,following all technical details and implementations
- PCI DSS management and infrastructure design
- Extensive knowledge of kubernetes and microservices
- Analysis and advantages of hybrid cloud
- Solution architect Google cloud platform
- Infrastructure as a code in cloud and on-prem with puppet ansible and terraform

# System administrator - Luxury Goods International LGI sa

contractor Temera sa 2011-2012 contractor IT Time sa 2010-2011

managing and responsible of end users tools , vpn cisco, active directory structure , lotus domino server and a first levelcontact for as400

#### Duties:

- Managing Mail Server Domino
- Management of mobile service on Blackberry
- Configuration and management VPN Cisco
- Active Directory management GPO
- AS400 jda , jd Edwards

# System administrator - Eprice srl

2008-2010

System administrator CED Gallarate and business farm Milano

#### Duties:

- Management remote data center on Colt (Milano) iNET (Settimo Milanese)
- Configuration windows and linux server based on vmware esx4 and esxi 4.1
- Deploy and configuration windows server 2000,
   2003, 2008 standard enterprise for business solution
- Deploy and configuration linux server for advanced internal solution (samba server, hw monitoring, performance monitoring, web employee portal, vpn server)
- Iscsi and fiber storage configuration and management
- Configuration and management of workstations working on Windows Xp e Windows 7.
- Server backup management tape DELL
- Network develop for company and other 30+ corner site

## **OTHER LANGUAGES**

	Understanding		Speaking		Writing
	Listening	Reading	Interaction	Production	_
English	B2	B2	B2	B2	B2
French	A2	A2	A2	A2	A2

#### **EDUCATION**

- 2003-2008
   Università degli studi dell'Insubria facoltà di informatica
   Information technology
- 1997- 2002 Pier Luigi Nervi I.T.Geometri